# JD Fillmore

#### **Career Profile**

Seasoned front end developer & UI designer with 7+ years experience working on corporate & national brand websites & SaaS products. Skilled in many of the major CMS platforms, JavaScript / CSS frameworks & design software. Dedicated to my craft through learning new technologies / techniques. Always enjoy my commitment to making the web a more user-friendly environment for everyone.

#### **Career Accomplishments**

- · Helped numerous businesses generate millions in revenue due to better performant websites
- · Saved costs and increased efficiencies by building reusable code libraries for projects
- Developed various Tim hortons projects, notably Every Cup Tells A Story and Tim's Rewards
- Work on VelocityEHS' webapp, that is used by over 14 million people in the EHS industry
- · Produced AODA AA compliant websites, giving the disabled a better internet experience

#### Skills

- HTML5CSS3 / SCSS
- GatsbyJSJAMStackNetlify
- YarnGulpFetch API
- Photoshop
- Google Tag ManagerSEO
- SketchInVision
- AgileScrum
- StorybookWordPress
- Google Analytics

• JavaScript
• Flexbox
• Bootstrap
• ReactJS

GithubNPM

• Git

AJAXAxiosJSON

# **Professional Experience**

#### VelocityEHS, Oakville, ON - Front End Developer (Contract)

June 2019 - Present

VelocityEHS is a cloud-based environment, health, safety (EHS) and sustainability solution designed to manage risk across organizations.

- · Develop front end for web application that is used by over 14 million people worldwide
- 50% increase in efficiency through developing a Storybook code component library
- Team lead for AODA WCAG AA Compliance & Storybook integration

#### Freelance, Remote - Front End Developer, UI / UX Designer

April 2013 - Present

Under the business name "Infused Agency", I help small businesses by building modern websites that perform better and increase revenue.

- · Capitalize on opportunity for learning new front end tech (ReactJS, GatsbyJS, Axios and more)
- 40% increase in client sales due to accessibility, speed and performance of client websites
- · 60% increase in all clients overall SEO rankings due to on-page and off-page SEO efforts

#### Thrillworks, Burlington, ON - Front End Developer

April 2018 - June 2019

Thrillworks is your solution for innovative web services that blend strategy, aesthetics, and technology to maximize your business.

- Developed GatsbyJS (ReactJS) and WordPress websites, WCAG AODA AA compliant
- 50% increase in team efficiency by co-developing an internal Storybook code component library
- 40% increase in organization by co-developing WorkShare an internal project tracking system
- Utilized Agile and Scrum methodologies

#### Virtual Image, Hamilton, ON - Front End Developer, UI / UX Designer, Project Manager

September 2016 - April 2018

March 2016 - September 2016

Virtual Image is a well established, progressive online marketing firm offering comprehensive web solutions.

- · Developed WordPress and static websites for a wide variety of clients
- 60% decrease in development time of websites due to component based libraries
- In charge of project and client management, leading to a 50% increase in satisfaction

#### Elite Digital, Toronto, ON – Front End Developer, UI / UX Designer (Contract)

Elite Digital is an award winning digital agency with headquarters in Toronto, Canada.

- First 2 days of employment, hand-coded and launched European Union website
- Developed static and responsive WordPress microsites for The NHL, Pepsi, Rogers and Disney
- 5 websites designed and launched within the first week of employment

### iOPW, Toronto, ON – Front End Developer, UI / UX Designer, Project Manager

August 2014 - March 2016

iOPW is a Canadian web-based technology company that provides businesses with the ability to increase their presence online.

- 2,000% increase in revenue due to successful design of rwardz.com front end and back end
- 30 responsive websites designed and developed
- Managed team of junior front end and back end developers, as well as numerous clients

### **SLK I.T. Solutions,** Toronto, ON – Front End Developer, UI / UX Designer, Project Manager

July 2013 - August 2014

SLK I.T. Solutions strives to be a leader in the information technology industry, keeping on top of the latest trends and technology.

- 20 responsive websites designed and developed
- 40% increase in client revenue due to on-page and off-page SEO efforts
- 60% increase in customer engagement due to newly designed and developed emails / websites

## Education